Pablo Philipps - Junior Developer

pabloignaciophilipps@gmail.com https://github.com/pablq

PERSONAL STATEMENT:

If I were to be granted an interview I think you'll find me to be a promising, if new, programmer. I have relevant experience with web development and I have a penchant for learning systems / languages quickly. Furthermore, I'm not averse to working in a support role, and I'm pretty good at talking to customers.

You might consider me a recent CS graduate although I am almost entirely self-taught through practice, asking questions, and online courses. My first love is making fine art, and I only became interested in CS recently as vehicle to make cutting edge work. But, as soon as I wrote my first line of code I immediately loved it, and I quickly came to appreciate CS for its own sake.

Writing code felt natural. It was an outlet to use my analytical mind without abandoning my creative side. It felt so right, in fact, that after only three months or so of serious learning I decided to quit my service job and dedicate myself full-time to learning.

A few months later, a Saint Louis non-profit called LaunchCode set me up with an interview at Fusion Marketing for an apprenticeship position. I was offered the position. I did well. And after some months Fusion brought me on as a full-fledged Junior Developer.

My experience at Fusion was a whirlwind. I spent the first few weeks asking questions, reading a lot, and built my first website: a tool for internal company use. It was a success. After that I was thrown into the mix. I was given projects with outside clients and real deadlines. As I proved my ability to adapt to projects and learn new technologies, I was trusted with increasingly complex and important assignments.

Of course, I made my share of mistakes, but I learned from them. I got a chance to work on many projects that were above my experience level. I learned how to interact positively with teammates and project managers. I learned how to deploy a product. I went from knowing absolutely nothing about development to knowing a solid something.

I understand that I have a ton yet to learn, and I realize that my skills need time to mature. But I'm proud of how far I've come, and I'm thankful for everyone that has helped me along the way.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Fusion Marketing, Saint Louis, MO, *Junior Developer*, Sept 2014 to Feb 2015 Fusion Marketing, Saint Louis, MO, *Apprentice*, May 2014 to Sept 2014 Trader Joe's, Chicago, IL / Brentwood, MO, *Crew Member*, August 2011 to March 2014

EDUCATION:

edX.org, 2014, 2015

Currently enrolled in *BerkeleyX's CS188x: Artificial Intelligence*. Completed *HarvardX's CS50x: Introduction to Computer Science*.

StrangeLoop, Saint Louis, MO, 2014

Colorado College, Colorado Springs, CO, 2005 to 2009

Degree: Bachelor of Arts, Major: Philosophy.

Oak Park and River Forest High School, Oak Park, IL, 2001 to 2005

National Hispanic Scholar

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS:

Languages: JavaScript, C, Java, Objective C, Python (novice), Ruby (novice) Mobile Development: iOS, Android, Phonegap/Cordova, deployment process Web Development:

Backend: **Node.js**, **Express**, **MySQL**, **MongoDB** Frontend: **AngularJS**, **HTML**, **CSS**, **ReactJS** (novice)

Hosting: GNU/Linux, Heroku, Amazon s3

Other: Git, documentation writing, Agile, vim, I am a very fast learner

PROJECT EXPERIENCE: (list not exhaustive)

At Fusion Marketing:

Built micro-site for World Cup viewing party RSVPs. http://www.budviewingparty.com

Overhauled client website. http://www.americanhoney.com

Maintained B to B incentive web application. http://abtapout.com

Updated universal Phonegap mobile app. Bommarito Automotive Group

Overhauled universal native mobile app. Motor Toolkit

Built CMS for mobile app. http://siemens-motor-toolkit.herokuapp.com

At home:

Built small iPhone game using the Core Graphics API. QAPG

Built personal website using Node.js. http://www.pablq.org

Writes image creation/manipulation scripts. https://github.com/pablq/mobot-sketch Wrote C program that demos various pathfinding algorithms.

https://github.com/pablq/basic_ai

RELATED INTERESTS:

Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Artificial Intelligence, 3D Modeling, 3D Printing.

REFERENCES:

Bradley Harris, VP, Technology at Fusion Marketing, bharris@thisisfusion.com Zach Lou, Education Director at LaunchCode, zach@launchcode.org

LINKS:

LaunchCode Website (I'm one of the featured videos at the bottom):

http://www.launchcode.org

My "Learner Story" on eDX:

https://www.edx.org/blog/edx-launchcode-learner-story-pablo

President Obama talking about LaunchCode:

http://www.c-span.org/video/?c4530637/lashana-lewis